Inventory of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Domestic Studies Program working papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Domestic Studies Program working papers
1980-2001
2009C60
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Domestic Studies
20 manuscript boxes (8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to economics and political science. Selected working papers available in digital format on the Hoover Institution website: http://www.hoover.org/research/domestic-studies-program/working-papers
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives between 1980-2009.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Relates to economics and political science. Selected working papers available in digital format on the Hoover Institution website: http://www.hoover.org/research/domestic-studies-program/working-papers.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Economics.; Political science.
Collection Contents
- 1980
  - Economic alysis of the Operation of Social Security Disability Insurance, Howard Marvel, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Absorptive Capacity and Economic Growth in an Oil-Exporting Nation, Karim Pakravan, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Bargaining under Uncertainty, W. Craig Riddell, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Contingent Fees for Personal Injury Litigation, Patricia Munch Danzon, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Decline in Black Teenage Employment, John Cogan, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Intertemporal Analysis of Taxation and Work Disincentives, Thomas E. MaCurdy, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Proposal for Monetary Reform, John Bilson, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Tax Treatment of Depreciation, Capital Gains, and Interest in an Inflationary Economy, Robert E. Hall, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Western Coal Tax Cartel, Martin Zimmerman/Christopher Alt, 1980 (Box 13)
- 1981
  - Black Teenage Employment and the Minimum Wage: A Time Series Analysis, John Cogan, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Current State of Bayesian Econometrics, Arnold Zellner, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Deregulation and Monetary Control Fifteen Months Later: A Postscript, Thomas Cargill/Gillian Garcia, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Economics of Gasoline Price and Allocation, Howard Marvel, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Estimation of the User's Cost for a Depletable Resource such as Oil, Karim Pakravan, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Exclusive Dealing, Howard Marvel, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Expected Inflation and Wage Changes in Canada, 1967-1981, W. Craig Riddell/Philip M. Smith (Box 13)
  - Hospital 'Profits': The Effects of Reimbursement Policies, Patricia Munch Danzon, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Intertemporal Model of Portfolio Choice and Human Capital Accumulation under Uncertainty with Extensions Incorporating Taxes, Consumer Durables, Imperfections in Capital Markets, and Nonseparable Preferences, Thomas E. MaCurdy, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Output, Income and Rank in Hierarchical Firms, Sherwin Rosen, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Philosophy and Objectives of Econometrics, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Simple Analytics of Fiscal interdependence, Melvyn Krauss, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Tax Exporting and the Commerce Clause: reflections on Commonwealth Edison, Charles E. McLure, Jr., 1981 (Box 12)
  - Use of Time Series Processes to Model the Error Structure of Earnings in a Longitudinal Data Analysis, Thomas E. MaCurdy, 1981 (Box 12)
- 1982
  - Are Inflation Rates Different for the Michael D. Hurd Elderly?, Michael J. Boskin/, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Debt and Current Account Deficit in Brazil, Olivier Jean Blanchard, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Effects of the U.S. Tax System on Housing Prices and Consumption, Richard F. Muth, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Firm: A Coordinator of Contracts, Yoram Barzel, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Fixed Employment Costs of Specialized Labor, Walter T. Oi, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Frequency and Severity of Medical Malpractice Claims, Patricia Munch Danzon, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Future of Capitalism: A Sociobiological Approach, Thomas Gale Moore, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Heterogeneous Firms and the Organization of Production, Walter Y. Oi, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Identification in Dynamic Linear Modelswith Rational Expectations, Olivier Jean Blanchard, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Incidence Analysis and the Supreme Court: An Examination of Four 1981 Cases, Charles E. McLure, Jr., 1982 (Box 12)
  - Intertemporal Model of Saving and Interest, Andrew B. Abel/Olivier Jean Blanchard, 1982 (Box 11)
  - On the Existence of Consistent Conjectural Equilibria in Models of Duopoly, Arthur J. Robson, 1982 (Box 13)
  - OPEC Versus the West: A Robust Duopoly Solution, Arthur J. Robson, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Optimum Pricing Policy under Stochastic Inflation, Eytan Sheshinski/Yoram Weiss, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Price Desynchronization and Price LevelInertia, Olivier Jean Blanchard, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Production and Inventory Behavior of the American Automobile Industry, Olivier Jean Blanchard, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Tests of Some Alternative Theories of Individual Choice Behavior, Raymond C. Battalio/Gerald P. Dwyer, Jr./ John H. Kagel, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Unemployment and Insurance, Sherwin Rosen, 1982 (Box 13)
- 1983
  - Adjustment Costs Durables and Aggregate Consumption, Ben S. Bernanke, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Competition among Pressure Groups for Political Influence, Gary S. Becker, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Congress and Redistribution, John A. Ferejohn, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Continuous Social Decision Procedures, John A. Ferejohn/Edward W. Packel, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Defining a Unitary Business: An Economist's view, Charles E. McLure, Jr., 1983 (Box 12)
  - Deregulating Rail and Truck Transportation, Thomas Gale Moore, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Economy, Elections, and Public Opinion, Seymour Martin Lipset, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Equilibrium Model of Industrial Employment, Hours, and Earnings,1923-1939, Ben S. Bernanke, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Housing Subsidies: Effects on Housing Decisions, Efficiency, and Equity, Harvey S. Rosen, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Images of Incumbents in Great Britain and the United States, Bruce E. Cain/John A. Ferejohn/Morris P. Fiorina, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Is Unemployment Involuntary?, Shelly Lundberg, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Liability Insurance and the Tort System: The Case of Medical Malpractice, Patricia Munch Danzon, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Life Cycles Institutions and Population Growth: A Theory of the Equilibrium Interest Rate in a Overlapping Generations Model, Robert J. Willis, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Medical Malpractice Insurance Crisis Revisited: Causes and Solutions, Patricia Munch Danzon, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Non-monetary effects of the financial crisis in the propagation of the great depression, Ben S. Bernanke, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Nonseparable Utility and Labor Supply, Finn E. Kydland, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Optimal Fiduciary Monetary Systems, Robert E. Hall, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Relationship between Wages and Benefits, Jeremy I. Bulow/Wayne Landsman, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Role of Candidates in Congressional Elections, Seymour Martin Lipset, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Role of Money in a Competitive Theory of Business Fluctuations, Finn E. Kydland, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Separation of the Redistributive and Allocative Functions of Government: A Public Choice Perspective, Marilyn R. Flowers/Patricia Munch Danzon, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Strategic Resource Extraction: When Easy Doesn't Do It, Jeremy I. Bulow/John D. Geankoplos, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Why Floating Exchange Rates Fail, Ronald McKinnon, 1983 (Box 12)
- 1984
  - On the Economic Approach to the Family, Yoram Ben-Porah, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Constituency Service Basis of the Personal Vote for U.S. Representatives and British MPS, Bruce E. Cain/John A. Ferejohn/Morris P. Fiorina, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Deregulation Rail and Truck Transportation (revised), Thomas Gale Moore, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Does the Tax System Favor Investment in High-Tech or Smokestack Industries? A Partial Answer Based on Differential Use of Assets, Don Fullerton/Andrew B. Lyon, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Economy of Israel: Maturing Through Crises, Yoram Ben-Porah, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Efficiency Wage Hypothesis: Applying a General Model of the Interaction between Labor Quantity and Quality, Carmel U. Chiswick, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Employment Tenure and On-the-Job Training in Japan and the United States, Masanori Hashimoto/John Raisian, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Entry Barriers and Multiproduct Oligopolistic Strategies, Matthew D. Gelfand/Pablo T. Spiller, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Excessive Federal Regulation: An Organizational Account, John E. Chubb, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Futures Market Backwardation under Risk Neutrality, Timothy F. Bresnahan/Pablo T. Spiller, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Golden Handcuffs: Wage Profiles with Word of Mouth Reputations, H. Lorne Carmichael, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Immigrant Generation and Income in Australia, Barry R. Chiswick/Paul W. Miller, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Incentive Effects of Taxes on Income from Capital: Alternative Policies in the 1980's, Don Fullerton/Yolanda Kodrzycki Henderson, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Information and Economic Analysis: A Perspective, Joseph E. Stiglitz, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Labor Market Status of Hispanic Men, 1900 to 1980, Barry R. Chiswick, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Minimum Wage Law and Youth Crimes: Time Series Evidence, Masanori Hashimoto, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Monetary Strategy with an Elastic PriceStandard, Robert E. Hall, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Multimarket Oligopoly, Jeremy I. Bulow/Paul D. Klemperer/ John D. Geanakoplos, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Natural Gas Exports in a Deregulation Environment, Henry M. Goldgerg/Terrence E. Daniel, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Optimal Monetary Institutions and Policy, Robert E. Hall, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Priced-Based Tests of Market Integration: An Application to the Uruguayan Banking Sector, Matthew D. Gelfand/Pablo T. Spiller, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Reputations for Safety: Market Performance and Policy Remedies, H. Lorne Carmichael, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Sophisticated Voting and Agenda Independence in the Distributive Politics Setting, John A. Ferejohn/ M. Fiorina/ R. McKelvey, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Taming the Deficits, Joseph A. Pechman, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Tort reform and the Role of Government in Private Insurance Markets, Patricia Munch Danzon, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Treble DamagesLimited Liability and Optimal Suing Time, Pablo T. Spiller, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Two Dimensional Theory of Ideology, John E. Chubb/Paul M. Sniderman/Michael G. Hagen, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Uncertainty Welfare Cost and the 'Adaptability' of U.S. Corporate Taxes, Don Fullerton/Andrew B. Lyon/Richard J. Rosen, 1984 (Box 12)
- 1985
  - Budget Deficits and the Exchange Rate, Emil-Maria Claassen/Melvyn Krauss, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Capital Controls and Covered Interest Between the Yen and the Dollar, Takatoshi Ito, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Causes and Consequences of the Dependence of Quality on Price, Joseph E. Stiglitz, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Community Development with Endogenous Land Use Controls, Dennis Epple/Thomas Romer/Radu Filimon, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Credit Markets and the Control of Capital, Joseph E. Stiglitz, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Earnings in Canada: The Roles of Immigrant Generation, French Ethnicity and Language, Barry R. Chiswick/Paul W. Miller, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Elasticity of Substitution Revisited: Effects of Secular Changes in Labor Force Structure, Carmel U. Chiswick, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Entry in Regulated Industries: An Information-Based Perspective, Joel S. Demski/David E. M. Sappington/Pablo T. Spiller, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Entry into Marriage and Parenthood by Young Men and Women: The Influence of Family Background, Robert T. Michael/Nancy Brandon Tuma, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Examination of Econometric Tests of the Propositions Central to the New Classical Macroeconomics, Roman Frydman/Peter Rappoport, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Geographic Market Definition under the Doj Merger Guidelines, David T. Scheffman/Pablo T. Spiller, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Government Deficits and Current Account, Juergen Schroeder, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Hidden Stimuli to Capital Formation: Debt and the Incomplete Adjustment of Financial Returns, Robert S. Chirinko/Stephen R. King, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Illegal Aliens: A Preliminary Report on an Employee-Employer Survey, Barry R. Chiswick, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Immigration Policy, Immigrant Workers, and the Human Capital of Natives,, Carmel U. Chiswick, 1985 (Box 13)
  - "Incentive Schemes with Multiple Agents and Bankruptcy Constraints ", Joel S. Demski/David E. M. Sappington/Pablo T. Spiller, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Incumbent Performance and Electoral Control, John A. Ferejohn, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Ineffectiveness of Effective Tax Rates on Business Investment, Robert S. Chirinko, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Investment and Tax Policy: A Perspective on Existing Models and Empirical Results, Robert S. Chirinko, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Is the New Immigration More Unskilled than the Old?, Barry R. Chiswick, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Lender-of-Last-Resort Function in the Context of National and International Financial Crises, Emil-Maria Claassen, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Logrolling in an Institutional Context: A Case Study of Food Stamps Legislation, John A. Ferejohn, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Methodological Issues in the Analysis of Immigrant Adjustment and Impact, Barry R. Chiswick, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Negative Net Foreign Position and Exchange Rate, Juergen Schroeder, 1985 (Box 14)
  - On the Extent of the Market: Wholesale Gasoline in the Northeastern United States, Pablo T. Spiller/Cliff J. Huang, 1985 (Box 14)
  - On Vertical Mergers, Pablo T. Spiller, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Ordinary Least Squares and Sample Selection Models of Health Care Demand: A Monte Carlo Comparison, Joel W. Hay/Robert Leu/Paul Rohrer, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Postal Savings System in Japan: A Roadblock to Interest Deregulation?, Toshihiko Hayashi, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Promises Promises: Campaign Contributions and the Reputation for Services, John A. Ferejohn/Roger G. Noll, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Reconciliation and the Size of the Budget, John A. Ferejohn/Keith Krehbiel, 1985 (Box 14)
  - State Restrictions on Local Debt: Their Role in Preventing Default, Dennis Epple/Chester Spatt, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Theory of Congressional Cycles: Solving the Puzzle of Change, Lawrence C. Dodd, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Thinking About Social Security Disability Policy in the 1980s and Beyond, Carolyn L. Weaver, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Trade Liberalization in Oligopolistic Industries: The Quota Case, Edward Buffie/Pablo T. Spiller, 1985 (Box 13)
  - U.S. Airline Deregulation: Its Effects on Passengers, Capital, and Labor, Thomas Gale Moore, 1985 (Box 12)
- 1986
  - Asymptotic Normality, When Regressors Have a Unit Root, Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Attendance Rates, Political Shirking, and the Effect of Post-Elective Office Employment, John R. Lott, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - Awarding Monopoly Franchises, Michael H. Riordan/David E. M. Sappington, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Comparable Worth and Discrimination in Labor Markets, Daniel R. Fischel/Edward P. Lazear, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Competition Compatibility and Standards: The Economics of Horses Penguins and Lemmings, Joseph Farrell/Garth Saloner, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Competitive Efficiency Wage Models with Keynesian Features, Charles Kahn/Dilip Mookherjee, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Competitive Human Markets, Interfamily Transfers, and Demographic Depression, Mikhail S. Bernstam, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Constant Recontracting Model of Sovereign Debt, Jeremy I. Bulow/Kenneth Rogoff, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Constitutional Regulation of Legislative Choice: The Political Consequences of Judicial Deference to Legislatures, William H. Riker/Barry R. Weingast, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Convergence of Least Square Learning Mechanisms in Self Referencial Linear Stochastic Models, Albert Marcet/Thomas J. Sargent, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Cooperation and Punishment under Repeated Majority Voting, Dennis Epple/Michael H. Riordan, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Crises' in Competitive Insurance Markets, Ralph A. Winter, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Deadweight Losses and the Richardian Equivalence Theorem, Gertrud M. Fremling/John R. Lott, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - Detrebling versus Decoupling Antitrust Damages: Lessons from A Theory of Enforcement, A. Mitchell Polinsky, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Disaggregate Equilibrium Model of the Tax Distortions among Assets Sectors and Industries, Don Fullerton/Yolanda Kodrzycki Henderson, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Disciplinary Role of Switching Suppliers: A Regulatory Interpretation, Joel S. Demski/David E. M. Sappington/Pablo T. Spiller, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Dividend Behavior for the Aggregate Stock Market, Terry A. Marsh/Robert C. Merton, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Dividend Innovations and Stock Price Volatility, Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Effect of Nontransferable Property Rights on the Efficiency of Political Markets: Some Evidence, John R. Lott, Jr., 1986 (Box 17)
  - Empirical Analysis of the Effect of Exchange Rate Changes on Goods Prices, Eugene Flood, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - Employment-at-Will, Job Security, and Work Incentives, Edward P. Lazear, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Equilibrium in Preemption Games with Complete Information, Kenneth Hendricks/Charles Wilson, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Equilibrium Investment under Uncertainty, Measurement Errors, and the Investment Accelerator, Thomas J. Sargent, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Equilibrium Model of Quits under Optimal Contracting, Charles M. Kahn, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Equilibrium Price Dynamics for an Experience Good, Kyle Bagwell/Michael H. Riordan, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Estimation of Transaction Costs in Arbitrage Models, Pablo T. Spiller/Robert O. Wood, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Evolution of Corporations: A Survey Article for the New Palgrave Dictionary of Political Economy, Robert Hessen, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Financing Public Goods, Russell D. Roberts, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Fiscal Incidence in Overlapping Generation Models, Christophe Chamley/Brian D. Wright, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Framework for Relating Microeconomic and Macroeconomic Evidence of Intertemporal Substitution, Thomas E. MaCurdy, 1986 (Box 15)
  - FTC Budget Process: Zero-Base Budgeting by Committee, Robert J. Mackay, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Full Versus Limited Imformation Estimation of a Rational Expectations Model: Some Numerical Comparisons, Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Global Competition and Exchange RateExposure, Eugene Flood, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - "Gulliver among the Lilliputians: Some Results on Competition and the Efficiency of Cournot Equilibrium ", John C. Hause, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Hadley v. Baxendale Revisited: The Forseability and the Mitigation Doctrines in Contract Law, Janet T. Landa, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Human Capital and Occupational Choice: A Reformulation, Morton Paglin/Anthony M. Rufolo, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Impact of Fundamental Tax Reform on the Allocation of Resources, Don Fullerton/Yolanda Kodrzycki Henderson, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Indemnity, Settlement, and Litigation or I'll be Suing You, John C. Hause, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Industrial Organization of Congress (or, Why Legislatures, Like Firms, are not Organized as Markets), Barry R. Weingast/William J. Marshall, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Information Returns and Bidding Behavior in OCS Auctions: 1954-1969, Kenneth Hendricks/Robert H. Porter/Bryan Boudreau, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Information, Incentives and Organizational Mode, Michael H. Riordan/David E. M. Sappington, 1986 (Box 16)
  - "Institutional Arrangement of Public Education: Puzzle of Exclusive Territories", John R. Lott, Jr., 1986 (Box 17)
  - Intertemporal Preferences and Labor Supply, V. Joseph Hotz/Finn E. Kydland/Guilherme L. Sedlacek, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Intertemporal Substitution in Consumption, Robert E. Hall, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Irrelevance of Government Foreign Exchange Operations,, Thomas J. Sargent/Bruce D. Smith, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Irrelevance of Open-Market Operations in Some Economies with Government Currency Being Dominated in Rate of Return,, Thomas J. Sargent/Bruce D. Smith, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Is Exclusive Dealing Anti-Competitive?, G. Franklin Mathewson/Ralph A. Winter, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Limited Contract Enforcement and Strategic Renegotiation, Gur Huberman/Charles M. Kahn, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Motives for Private Income Transfers, Donald Cox, 1986 (Box 14)
  - News from the U.S. and Japan: Which Moves the Yen/Dollar Exchange Rate?, Takatoshi Ito/V. Vance Roley, 1986 (Box 15)
  - North American Labor Movements: A Comparative Perspective, Seymour Martin Lipset, 1986 (Box 15)
  - "Operating Exposure to Exchange Rates: A Synthesis ", Eugene Flood, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - Origin of Speculative Limits, Virginia Grace France, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Pay Equality and Industrial Politics, Edward P. Lazear, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Political Cheating, John R. Lott, Jr., 1986 (Box 17)
  - Power to Veto, Robert J. Mackay/Carolyn L. Weaver, 1986 (Box 14)
  - PredationMergers and Incomplete Information, Garth Saloner, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Product Differentiation, B. Curtis Eaton/Richard G. Lipsey, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Quantity Theory of Money, Milton Friedman, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Rand Health Insurance Study: a Critique, Bruce L. Welch/Joel W. Hay/Daniel S. Miller/Randall J. Olsen/Robert M. Rippey/Annemarie S. Welch, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Reconsideration of the Railroad Problem: The Economics and Politics of the Interstate Commerce Act, Thomas W. Gilligan/William J. Marshal/Barry R. Weingast, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Relation between Price and Marginal Cost in U.S. Industry, Robert E. Hall, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Rethinking Social Welfare: U.S. and U.S.S.R. in Comparative Perspective, Alex Inkeles, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Should Tax Revenue Be Minimized when Financing Public Goods, Russell D. Roberts, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Should the Wealthy Be Able to 'Buy Justice'?, John R. Lott, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - Simple, Positive Semi-Definite, Heteroskedasticity and Autocorrelation Consistent Covariance Matrix, Whitney K. Newey/Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Socio-Economic Organization of Honeybee Colonies: A Transaction Costs Approach, Janet T. Landa/Anthony Wallis, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Specification Test for Speculative Bubbles, Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Standard Monetary Model and the Variability of the Deutschemark-Dollar Exchange Rate, Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 16)
  - State as the Marriage Partner of Last Resort: New Findings on Minimum Wage, Youth Joblessness, Welfare, and Single Motherhood in the United States, 1960-1980, Mikhail S. Bernstam/Peter L. Swan, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Targeting Nominal Income: A Note, Kenneth D. West, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Theory of Reinforcement and the Timing of Payments, Edward P. Lazear, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Tobin's Q and Financial Policy, Robert S. Chirinko, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Two-Sided Uncertainty and 'Up-or-Out' Contract, Charles Kahn/Gur Huberman, 1986 (Box 16)
  - U.S. Taxation of Foreign-Source Earnings and Intrafirm Financing and Reimittance Decisions, Eugene Flood, Jr., 1986 (Box 16)
  - US Social Security and Conditions of Low- Fertility, Rita Ricardo-Campbell, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Use of Complicated Models as Explanations: A Re-Examination of Williamson's Late 19th Century America, Charles M. Kahn, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Wealth--The Support of Institutions and the Limits of Control, B. Curtis Eaton/William D. White, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Welfare Implications of Costly Litigation in the Theory of Liability, A. Mitchell Polinsky/Daniel L. Rubinfeld, 1986 (Box 15)